JIMMY METTS SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

615-579-8520

JIMMYMETTSDEV@GMAIL.COM

in LINKEDIN.COM/IN/JIMMYMETTS

GITHUB.COM/JIMMYMETTS

PROFILE

After spending many years in the music industry, I wanted to change careers and needed a field with a growing job market that rewards hard work. I became aware of coding though a close family member's interest in the field a year ago and was pulled even closer when they graduated from Nashville Software School's Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp. I find software development to be constantly challenging and at the same time very rewarding. I enjoy researching, learning and implementing new techniques. I am looking forward to applying my skills in software development and believe with my varied work experience I will be an asset to any team.

CAPSTONE PROJECTS

Show Poster NOW!:

github.com/jimmymetts/Capstone-one

Show Poster NOW! is an application built using React, React-PDF, ReactStrap and CSS, that will allow artists & musicians to quickly create a digital, downloadable show poster from basic templates with limited, but well designed options. This will simplify and streamline the process of designing a show poster to promote an upcoming event, especially if you need it fast.

EDUCATION

- Nashville Software School
 Full Stack Web Dev Boot Camp
- Belmont University
 B.A., Music Business
- Mississippi State University
 Computer Science no degree

EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER | APRIL 2019 - PRESENT

Intensive full-time software development boot camp focusing on full stack fundamentals and problem solving with both individual and team-based projects. **Tech Stack:** HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Reactstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, ReactJS, C#, .NET, SQL

- Created single page apps with ReactJS, JavaScript and JQuery
- Multiple API using Ajax with CRUD methods to request, receive and send JSON data to a server
- Worked on group projects creating single page apps with JavaScript, JQuery, ReactJS and web apps with C#, .Net and SQL
- Created HTML5 and CSS animations for webpages
- Experience with NPM packages

TORQUE ENTERTAINMENT

PRESIDENT | FEBRUARY 2016-NOVEMBER 2018

- Managing day-to-day details of growing artist footprint and development including setting up social media marketing and PR campaigns for releases, product/merchandise development & management, budgeting, setting up video shoots, photo shoots, studio recordings and record production
- Auditioning and rehearsing new band members and advancing live shows

STARSTRUCK WRITERS GROUP (REBA MCENTIRE)

GENERAL MANAGER | JANUARY 2014-SEPTEMBER 2015

- General Manager for Starstruck Entertainment's publishing division, Starstruck Writers Group
- Responsibilities included daily operation of the publishing division, exploitation of copyrights, managing writer schedules & co-writes for 7 staff writers, reviewing contracts, tracking royalty streams and overseeing the administration of the publishing catalog

CAULEY MUSIC GROUP / VOXHALL RECORDS

VP/COO | JANUARY 2011-NOVEMBER 2013

- Exploitation of copyrights, managing writer schedules & co-writes for staff writers, reviewing contracts, tracking royalty streams and overseeing the administration of the publishing catalog
- Launched new record label, Voxhall Records
- Album production, engineering, art direction, marketing/PR, radio promotion
- Produced and engineered Voxhall's first release, "Grace Notes", on twotime Grammy winner Carl Jackson-January, 2013

PANAMA CITY BEACH VISITORS BUREAU

TALENT BUYER/COORDINATOR | JULY 2010-OCTOBER 2010

- Scheduled/booked artist concerts for Panama City Beach, Florida tourism in conjunction with the BP oil spill
- \$300,000 talent budget, \$3 million total budget for concert series production
- Artists included Amy Grant, Chris Tomlin, Michael W. Smith, Point of Grace, Sara Evans & John Rich

STROUDAVARIOUS RECORDS

VP A&R / PUBLISHING | AUGUST 2008-JULY 2010

- Overseeing artist projects for 10 plus artists, finding new song material, auditioning and rehearsing new band members
- Management duties for new artists included advancing radio and concert tour dates, coordinating with production teams, scheduling rehearsals, band member invoices for rehearsals, backline, hotel arrangements and bus arrangements
- Manage all aspects of publishing company's day-to-day operations including managing 8 staff writers and the exploitation of song catalog to major label artists

MALACO MUSIC

VP OF NASHVILLE OPERATIONS | JUNE 1997-AUGUST 2008

- Managed all aspects of the Nashville office
- Streamlined staff by 25% while increasing released singles by 75%, including the company's first #1 song, "Mayberry" by Rascal Flatts
- SESAC Publisher of the Year 2004